Shahin Yusifli

I have over two years of experience in data analysis and data engineering. In different projects, I have used **Power BI**, **SQL Server Analysis Service**, **Azure SQL Data Warehouse**, **Azure Databricks**, **Azure Data Factory**, **Oracle BI**, **PL/SQL**, **Airflow**, **and Git/GitHub**. Also, I am so motivated and open to new technologies, and work disciplines.

CONTACTS

Phone: +37256385105 | Email: sahinyusifli98@gmail.com |

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/shahin-yusifli | GitHub: github.com/shahinyusifli |

Address: Ehitajate tee 5, 12616 Tallinn, TALLINN, Estonia

EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst/Engineer, Agile Solutions, 01/2020 – 06/2021

Creating data-driven infrastructure for the Azerbaijan Republic State Migration Service and creating and maintaining ETL pipelines and reporting infrastructure for the data warehouse of Unibank

- I have created reports that consist of quantitative bivariate and univariate analysis and modeling data in **Power**BI
- I have created and maintained tabular models in SQL Server Analysis Service with Microsoft Studio.
- I was responsible for cleaning and transforming data with Apache Airflow.
- I have produced and updated **Airflow** workflow documentation, including task dependencies, **DAG** (**Directed Acyclic Graph**) definitions, and workflow schedules.
- I have maintained and created stored procedures in **Oracle** with **PL/SQL Schema objects** such as **Cursors**, **Triggers**, and **Stored Procedures** for **ELT** pipelines.
- I have created more than 80 ETL pipelines in Azure Databricks from different external and internal data sources to Azure SQL Data Warehouse and monitoring these pipelines runs in Azure Data Factory.
- I have used MySQL sys Schema and MySQL Performance Schema for monitoring and getting data to daily performance reports of ELT pipelines.

Technologies: Power BI, SQL Server Analysis Service, Apache Airflow, PL/SQL, Azure Databricks, Azure Data Factory, Azure SQL Data Warehouse, MySQL

Software Engineer, SOLITA OÜ, 03/2022 – 06/2023

Provide ETL pipelines for business intelligence solutions in the **PS Lifestyle project** (https://pslifestyle-app.net/) and an internal discussion form for DevAcademy of Solita.

- I have contributed to the performance improvement of MySQL by tuning server options and query optimization.
- I have developed data pipelines for Dashboard, Login, and Registration pages for an internal communication app for DevAcademy of Solita with JavaScript, React, Cypress, Jest, Bootstrap, and .NET 6 WEB API.
- I have implemented the API networking for the Questionnaire, Recommendations, and Results functionality of the PS Lifestyle app with **TypeScript**, **React**, **Tailwind CSS**, **and Firebase**.
- I have built **Power BI** reports with qualitative bivariate and univariate analyses in the PS Lifestyle project.

Technologies: C#, NET Web API, Power BI, MySQL, TypeScript, JavaScript, React, Bootstrap, Azure Functions, Azure Logic Apps.

EDUCATION

Computer and Systems Engineering (MSc), Tallinn University of Technology, 06/2021 - 06/2023. Management of Information Systems (MSc), Baku Engineering University, 06/2019 - 06/2021. Mechatronics, Robotics, and Automation Engineering (BSc), Azerbaijan Oil and Industry University, 06/2015 - 06/2019.

SKILLS

- Power BI, SQL Server Analysis
 Service, Apache Airflow, PL/SQL
- · JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, React, Cypress, Jest, Bootstrap, Tailwind

- · Azure Databricks, Azure Data Factory, Azure SQL Data Warehouse, MySQL
- · C#. NET Web API, Java, Spring Boot, Python, Django

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- Data operations of company database with PL/SQL (Oracle, PL/SQL, SQL Developer) The
 project consists of data operations of the company database where schema objects (triggers,
 functions, stored procedures, cursors, and packages) are used.
 https://github.com/shahinyusifli/SQL daily tasks small company
- Quantitive data analytics of FDIC failed banks dataset (Power BI, DAX) Example univariate
 and bivariate visualizations in Power BI.
 https://github.com/shahinyusifli/data-analysis-of-fdic-failed-banks
- Web API for movie websites (Java, Spring Boot, MongoDB) People can create, delete, edit, and add reviews to movies.
 https://github.com/shahinyusifli/movie list API
- Social media platform (.NET Web API, React, SQL, React Material UI) People can share and rate their posts.
 https://github.com/shahinyusifli/discussion_forum_forum_end
- Farm data analysis (Django, SQL, Pandas, Data Visualization, Bootstrap) This project aims to upload and process CSV files using filters with various granularities. Data can be uploaded to databases using Pandas and Numpy which are filtered and verified. https://github.com/shahinyusifli/solita_dev_academy

LANGUAGES

- English Full Professional Proficiency
- Azerbaijani Native or Bilingual Proficiency
- Estonian Elementary Proficiency